decoration, the Order of the Green Banner, which he had conferred upon himself.
In the general rejoicings, the unfortunate affair of the banknotes was forgotten.
It was a few days later than this that the pigs came upon a case of whiskey in
the cellars of the farmhouse.
It had been overlooked at the time when the house was first occupied.
That night, there came from the farmhouse the sound of loud singing, in
which, to everyone's surprise, the strains of Beasts of England were mixed up.
At about half past nine, Napoleon, wearing an old bowler hat of Mr.
Jones's, was distinctly
seen to emerge from the back door, gallop rapidly round the yard, and disappear indoors again.
But in the morning, a deep silence hung over the farmhouse.
Not a pig appeared to be stirring.
It was nearly nine o'clock when Squealer made his appearance, walking slowly and
dejectedly, his eyes dull, his tail hanging limply behind him,
and with every appearance of being seriously ill.
He called the animals together and told them that he had a terrible piece of news to impart.
Comrade Napoleon was dying.
A cry of lamentation went up.
Straw was laid down outside the doors of the farmhouse, and the animals walked on tiptoe.
With tears in their eyes, they asked one another what they should do if their
leader were taken away from them.
A rumor went round that Snowball had, after all, contrived to introduce poison
into Napoleon's food.
At 11 o'clock, Squealer came out to make another announcement.
As his last act upon Earth, Comrade Napoleon had pronounced a solemn decree.
The drinking of alcohol was to be punished by death.
By the evening, however, Napoleon appeared to be somewhat better, and the
following morning Squealer was able to tell them that he was well on the way to recovery.
By the evening of that day, Napoleon was back at work, and on the next day it was
learned that he had instructed Whymper to purchase in Willingdon some booklets
on brewing and distilling.
A week later, Napoleon gave orders that the small paddock beyond the orchard,
which it had previously been intended to set aside as a grazing ground for
animals who were past work, was to be plowed up.
It was given out that the pasture was exhausted and needed reseeding,
but it soon became known that Napoleon intended to sow it with barley.
About this time, there occurred a strange incident which hardly anyone was able to understand.
One night, at about 12:00, there was a loud crash in the yard, and the animals
rushed out of their stalls.
It was a moonlit night.
At the foot of the end wall of the big barn, where the Seven Commandments were
written, there lay a ladder broken in two pieces.
Squealer, temporarily stunned, was sprawling beside it, and near at hand,
there lay a lantern, a paintbrush, and an overturned pot of white paint.
The dogs immediately made a ring round Squealer and escorted him back to the
farmhouse as soon as he was able to walk.
None of the animals could form any idea as to what this meant, except old
Benjamin, who nodded his muzzle with a knowing air and seemed to understand,
but would say nothing.